

Ahsan Javed

+923244772022 ahsanjaveduog@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

Did MSCS from UET, Lhr. Also worked in Atlas Insurance for almost 3years, as part of one large-scale project, and also build many medium-sized projects from requirements gathering to development in my current organization. Have a keen interest in Web and Mobile application development and IT management. Also, get a diploma in Android Development from EVS, CEH from Corvit Systems, and Laravel Development from PNY Trainings.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- Dev Tools: Android Studio, Eclipse, Unity, Visual Studio Code.
- Framework: Laravel
- Database: SQLite, Firebase(cloud), MySQL
- Languages: Java, C#, PHP
- Others: JSON, XML, Firebase, Third Party Apis, Rest Apis

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

University of Engineering and Technology, Lahore. MS in Computer Science 2020 - 2023

University of Gujrat, Lhr Campus. BS in Software Engineering 2014 - 2018

WORK HISTORY

Android/Web Developer/Operations

Atlas Group

February 2020 to Present

- Developed user-friendly android applications for the client.
- Developed web portal in laravel framework.
- Validated completed Application including testing and debugging of code.
- Parse the data in JSON form using Volley/Retrofit and Rest Apis. Also using MVVM architecture.
- Able to integrate the push notification module using FCM HTTP protocol.

Android Developer

Absomech

January 2019 to January 2020

- Successfully developed the 3 large-scale, userfriendly, ultra-high performance android applications.
- Able to integrate the third-party API and parse the data from JSON into the application.
- Converted the PSD design into mobile UI using XML.
- Able to store and fetch the data into the cloud(Firebase).
- Also used the SQLite database for managing a large amount of data.
- Used new coded solutions that increase the application performance.
- Integrated ad networks like Admob, unity ads, Chartboost, startApp ads
- Published apps on the play store

PROJECTS

• Risk Management Portal

Devloped project on laravel integrated with the GIS. Also implement the risk location alerts, followup visits and reports management.

• Health Claims

Developed and deployed the web application (Laravel). Insured cover types, limits, hospitalizations, IPD etc. All relevant features were build in the app.

HACPL

It connects with the server using Restful Apis, The Pie Charts and Line Graphs show the business which enhances the usability of the management users. It also contains different reports example, date wise vehicle business or development officer incentives, also shows the dealership business status.

Dashboard

This dashboard tells the users about the company business in both conventional and takaful. Also build reports of direct, inward, outward buisness. Department wise reports also build. Nadra and nacta check also implemented in the dashboard.

Atlas Unify

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.pk.atlas.ail.atlasunify

Atlas Insurance comes with the idea of bringing all of these tasks to your fingertips with "Atlas Unify" because modern problems need modern solutions. An app providing all the information to the insured regarding policy detail, intimation of claims, surveyor's information, and claim status is just a click away. Atlas Unify will intimate you 15 days before the policy expires through its renewal feature and keeps you updated with all the latest news and offers related to Atlas Insurance. In addition to it, Atlas Unify gives you the facility to quote for your asset's insurance either you are a registered user or not. Atlas Unify makes it easy for you because apart from your assets Atlas Insurance saves your time too because we care for you.

Leasing App

Connects the booking and verification forms with the backend server using the network library. Also, implement the search and verify functions in it.

Islamic App

Islamic App contains the animated Qibla direction compass and prayer time. Complete Quran-e-Pak, which you can access through Para(juz) or also by Surah with translation. It also features online Islamic books and Islamic Quote.

Kids' Education

It contains more than 15 categories and 300+ items for kids to learn and recognize items. It also contains sound and images of 300+ items. It also contains 3 quiz games.